<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>New Zealand &#8211; WW Cam Britannica</title>
	<atom:link href="https://ww.cam.britannica.com/tag/new-zealand/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 18:12:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/wwcam.png</url>
	<title>New Zealand &#8211; WW Cam Britannica</title>
	<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Jacinda Ardern got the title of &#8216;Dame&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/jacinda-ardern-got-the-title-of-dame/</link>
					<comments>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/jacinda-ardern-got-the-title-of-dame/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gambabu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 18:12:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Govt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/zolakaert/?p=38</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Zealand has awarded former Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern the title of &#8216;Dame&#8217;, one of the country&#8217;s highest honours. He was given the title on Monday for his role after the Christchurch mosque attack in 2019 and his leadership in the corona pandemic. The title Dame is primarily given to women. It is equivalent to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>New Zealand has awarded former Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern the title of &#8216;Dame&#8217;, one of the country&#8217;s highest honours. He was given the title on Monday for his role after the Christchurch mosque attack in 2019 and his leadership in the corona pandemic. The title Dame is primarily given to women. It is equivalent to the royal title of &#8216;knight&#8217;. &#8216;Knight&#8217; is one of the highest honors conferred by the King of the United Kingdom.</p>



<p>The 42-year-old Ardern announced her resignation from the post of Prime Minister of New Zealand and politics last January. Chris Hipkins became the Prime Minister of New Zealand as his successor. He said Ardern had been given the title of Dame, one of the country&#8217;s highest honours, at a ceremony marking the birthday and coronation of King Charles III.</p>



<p>Britain&#8217;s King Charles III was inaugurated on May 6. He is also the head of state of New Zealand.</p>



<p>Hipkins said Dame Jacinda Ardern served as Prime Minister of New Zealand from 2017 to 2013. He was recognized for the important role he played during the great challenges New Zealand has gone through in modern times.</p>



<p>On receiving the new title, Ardern said, &#8216;I was ambivalent about accepting this honour. Because most of these works are the product of the collective experience of New Zealanders.&#8217;</p>



<p>He was widely popular during the election of Prime Minister of New Zealand for a second term in 2020. But as the country&#8217;s inflation and cost of living rose, his popularity was waning. In this situation, he left the prime ministership and politics.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/jacinda-ardern-got-the-title-of-dame/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
