<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>WW Cam Britannica</title>
	<atom:link href="https://ww.cam.britannica.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 06:45:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/wwcam.png</url>
	<title>WW Cam Britannica</title>
	<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>1600 earthquakes in Iceland in one day</title>
		<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/1600-earthquakes-in-iceland-in-one-day/</link>
					<comments>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/1600-earthquakes-in-iceland-in-one-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gambabu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 06:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earthquake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iceland]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ww.cam.britannica.com/?p=131</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1,600 earthquakes were felt in Reykjavík, the capital of Iceland, in one day. Officials in the country say so many earthquakes could trigger lava eruptions from the volcano. The Iceland Meteorological Office (IMO) said the first earthquake was felt at 4pm local time last Tuesday. Its origin was 40 km from the capital under the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>1,600 earthquakes were felt in Reykjavík, the capital of Iceland, in one day. Officials in the country say so many earthquakes could trigger lava eruptions from the volcano.</p>



<p>The Iceland Meteorological Office (IMO) said the first earthquake was felt at 4pm local time last Tuesday. Its origin was 40 km from the capital under the Fagradashpiach hill. Fagradaspiach is located on a volcano. The volcano has erupted twice in the past two years — once in 2021, then in 2022.</p>



<p>But till the last news no lava eruption was seen anywhere. Concerned persons fear that the eruption may start very soon.</p>



<p>According to IMO data, only four of these earthquakes had a magnitude greater than four, which is considered a mild earthquake.</p>



<p>Due to the earthquake, the aviation alert was changed from &#8216;green&#8217; to &#8216;yellow&#8217;.</p>



<p>Iceland is the most active volcanic region in Europe.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/1600-earthquakes-in-iceland-in-one-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UN chief calls on world to make troubled Haiti ‘top priority’</title>
		<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/un-chief-calls-on-world-to-make-troubled-haiti-top-priority/</link>
					<comments>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/un-chief-calls-on-world-to-make-troubled-haiti-top-priority/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gambabu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 10:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/tvone-tv/?p=63</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On a visit to spotlight violence and chaos in Haiti, the UN secretary-general on Saturday called for a robust international effort to help the country’s beleaguered police in fighting rampant criminal gangs. For months, Antonio Guterres has raised the alarm bell about the situation in the Western Hemisphere’s poorest country, which has been wracked by [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>On a visit to spotlight violence and chaos in Haiti, the UN secretary-general on Saturday called for a robust international effort to help the country’s beleaguered police in fighting rampant criminal gangs.</p>



<p>For months, Antonio Guterres has raised the alarm bell about the situation in the Western Hemisphere’s poorest country, which has been wracked by spiralling violence, a worsening public health situation and political instability.</p>



<p>But he traveled to Port-au-Prince—his first visit to Haiti as head of the United Nations—to make his point on the ground.</p>



<p>“We must put Haiti on the international political map, and make the tragedy of the Haitian people the international community’s top priority,” Guterres told a press conference.</p>



<p>“I met Haitians, and I felt the exhaustion of a population that has been facing a cascade of crises and unbearable living conditions for too long,” he said.</p>



<p>“This is not the time to forget about Haiti,” Guterres said after meeting with Prime Minister Ariel Henry, and other political and civil society leaders.</p>



<p>Guterres urged the UN Security Council, which is due to discuss the Haiti situation later this month, “to authorize the immediate deployment of a robust international security force.”</p>



<p>In October, he relayed Henry’s request for a non-UN force to support the overwhelmed national police force.</p>



<p>But the call has gone unheeded. A few countries have indicated their willingness to participate, but none has volunteered to lead an operation in a country where multiple past foreign interventions have become mired.</p>



<p>“I call on those states that have the capacity to provide a robust security force to stop hesitating and be ready to follow a Security Council decision,” Guterres said.</p>



<p>“Every day counts. If we don’t act now, instability and violence will have a lasting impact on generations of Haitians.”</p>



<p><strong>‘Widespread sexual violence’</strong></p>



<p>UN officials in recent months have offered increasingly grim assessments of the impact of gang shootings, kidnappings and rapes on the Haitian population.</p>



<p>“Port-au-Prince is surrounded by armed gangs blocking the main roads leading to the northern and southern departments, controlling access to water, food and health care,” Guterres said Saturday.</p>



<p>He condemned “in the strongest possible terms the widespread sexual violence used by armed gangs as a weapon to instill fear.”</p>



<p>Earlier in the week, UNICEF executive director Catherine Russell said after a trip to Port-au-Prince that the world was “failing the Haitian people.”</p>



<p>She recounted the horrific story of an 11-year-old girl who was kidnapped by five men—and raped by three of them.</p>



<p>“She was eight months pregnant when we spoke and gave birth just a few days later,” Russell said, recalling that armed gangs control more than 60 percent of the capital and large swathes of the countryside.</p>



<p>Almost half the population, or 5.2 million people, are in need of humanitarian assistance, including almost three million children.</p>



<p>No elections have been held since 2016, and Henry, appointed prime minister just days before the assassination of president Jovenel Moise in July 2021, faces questions about his legitimacy.</p>



<p>Guterres said he had “frank exchanges” with Henry and others about the “need for a political agreement to put an end to the crisis,” without offering specifics.</p>



<p>He called on civic leaders to “overcome their personal interests and make concessions in order to facilitate the emergence of a common vision and a viable and credible electoral path.”</p>



<p>After Haiti, Guterres travels to Trinidad and Tobago for a Caribbean Community (Caricom) summit, where issues surrounding Haiti will be discussed.</p>



<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken also will attend the summit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/un-chief-calls-on-world-to-make-troubled-haiti-top-priority/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Southeast Asia has not seen such a temperature in 200 years</title>
		<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/southeast-asia-has-not-seen-such-a-temperature-in-200-years/</link>
					<comments>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/southeast-asia-has-not-seen-such-a-temperature-in-200-years/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gambabu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 05:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temperature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Translation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/top85/?p=50</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fires were intense in South and Southeast Asia in April and May. That blaze is still going on. Due to heat and humidity, the people of this region are at high risk of heat stroke, heart disease, kidney problems and even death due to dehydration. CNN&#8217;s Sarlotta Doto , Christina Schweda and Lou Robinson detail the story . Every day countless mopeds (motorcycles [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Fires were intense in South and Southeast Asia in April and May. That blaze is still going on. Due to heat and humidity, the people of this region are at high risk of heat stroke, heart disease, kidney problems and even death due to dehydration. <strong>CNN&#8217;s Sarlotta Doto</strong> , <strong>Christina Schweda</strong> and <strong>Lou Robinson</strong> detail the story .</p>



<p>Every day countless mopeds (motorcycles with pedals) and motorbikes ply the busy streets of Hanoi, Vietnam. Some are going to work, some are transporting passengers. Others are delivering parcels or food to consumers.</p>



<p>One such person is Fong (42). At five in the morning he started working with the moped. He left for work early in the morning to escape the unbearable heat. Worked for 12 hours straight.</p>



<p>But in the last two months, terrible fires have engulfed the entire country. Temperatures hover around 40 degrees Celsius (104 degrees Fahrenheit) every day. This unbearable situation made Fong&#8217;s job very difficult. Wear a hat while going out to work to protect yourself from the extreme heat. Keep wet towels and a few bottles of water with you.</p>



<p>Temperatures in Hanoi averaged over 32 degrees Celsius throughout the month of May.</p>



<p>Fong was saying, &#8216;I have to stop working if I get heat stroke. My family won&#8217;t survive in this.&#8217;</p>



<p>Fong uses a small umbrella to protect the mobile phone, the most important part of his job, from the heat. He uses ride sharing app &#8216;Grub&#8217; platform for work. If the phone breaks for some reason or the battery gets damaged due to heat, his income<br>will be cut off.</p>



<p>Din Van Hung (53) was working as a cleaner in Dong Da area of ​​Hanoi. He cleaned the garbage on the busy road throughout the day. Din Bhan said, &#8216;Dry heat cannot be avoided in the afternoon and early afternoon. Excessive temperature emits an unbearable odor from garbage. My job has become more difficult now. The heat is having an adverse effect on the health of me and other workers.&#8217;</p>



<p>Din Bhan added, &#8216;I try to start work early in the morning and in the afternoon or evening. In the afternoon when the temperature is at extremes, I take shade on the sidewalk. Then in the afternoon I started working again.&#8217;</p>



<p>In Southeast Asia, including Vietnam, Phong and Din Bhan are the image of millions of people working in the open air, including drivers, hawkers, cleaners, construction workers, farmers. They have to work under record pressure.</p>



<p>These workers suffer disproportionately in such adverse weather conditions. The extreme heat is affecting their health and has already made their occupation dangerous.</p>



<p>Generally, April and May are the hottest months in Southeast Asian countries. The temperature rises considerably in this region before the onset of monsoon rains. But this time the temperature has reached a level that has never been seen before. The tourism industry of Thailand and Vietnam is also affected.</p>



<p>Maximiliano Herrera, who works on climate, analyzed the weather data and said that on April 15, Thailand had the highest temperature in the country&#8217;s history at 45.4 degrees Celsius (114 degrees Fahrenheit). Similarly, neighboring Laos recorded two consecutive days of 43.5 degrees Celsius (110 degrees Fahrenheit) in May. And at the beginning of May, Vietnam had the highest temperature in the history of that country, which was 44.2 degrees Celsius.</p>



<p>Herrera described the situation as an &#8216;unending barrage of brutality&#8217;. According to him, this fire will continue throughout the month of June. Vietnam broke the record for the hottest June in their history (43.8 degrees Celsius) on June 1. Time will tell what will happen in the remaining 29 days.</p>



<p>According to a report by World Weather Attribution (WWA), an international alliance of scientists, the kind of fire that is going on in Southeast Asia is seen once in 200 years. But such a scenario is &#8216;virtually impossible&#8217; without man-made climate change.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Damage is more in humidity</h2>



<p>The scorching heat can become even more unbearable in Southeast Asia due to high humidity. Because, humidity with high temperature increases the heat in the human body and the body does not cool down easily.</p>



<p>Heat related illnesses such as heat stroke, fatigue are not good signs. It can be life threatening. Pregnant women, heart patients, kidney patients and people with diabetes are especially at risk.</p>



<p>Mariam Zakaria, research associate at Imperial College London, said, &#8220;When the humidity is too high, the body sweats to cool itself down.&#8221; But due to non-evaporation of sweat, severe dehydration occurs in the body. If it becomes severe it can lead to heat stroke and even death. This is why humid heat is more dangerous than dry heat.</p>



<p>To understand the human health risks of humid heat, scientists usually calculate the &#8216;feels-like&#8217; temperature. They factor in both temperature and humidity to calculate how it feels. Wind speed is also often taken into account.</p>



<p>The perceived temperature is often much higher than the normal temperature. Much more accurate information is available from the perceived temperature of how much it affects the human body.</p>



<p>Six Southeast Asian countries (Thailand, Vietnam, Cambodia, Laos, Malaysia and Myanmar) experienced daily temperatures of 40 degrees Celsius or more between early April and late May, according to an analysis of data from the Copernicus Climate Change Service. This level is considered above the risk limit. People with health problems and not used to such heat are particularly at risk.</p>



<p>Thailand experienced 20 days in April and 10 days in May with temperatures above 46 degrees Celsius. Temperatures at this stage are quite &#8216;extreme&#8217; and are considered life-threatening. If there is moisture with it, there is no question.</p>



<p>Vietnam, Cambodia, Laos and Malaysia experienced extreme temperatures during April–May. Before the cyclone cleared, there was a near-fire in Myanmar for 12 days.</p>



<p>According to World Weather Attribution, wildfires in Southeast Asia in April–May caused illness, road damage<br>, fires, and school closures. However, not much is known about the actual death toll.</p>



<p>According to the agency&#8217;s report, the perceived temperature is 2 degrees above normal due to climate change.</p>



<p>Mariam Zakaria, one of the authors of World Weather Attribution, said that as the atmosphere warms, its capacity to hold moisture increases. It also increases the risk of humid heat waves.</p>



<p>According to the report, if global warming continues to increase by 2 degrees Celsius, humid temperatures could increase 10 times.</p>



<p>Projections from the United Nations&#8217; Human Climate Horizons show that if temperatures rise at the same rate, fires in Thailand will kill 30 people per million in two decades and more than 130 people by the end of this century. In the case of Myanmar, these numbers will be 30 and 520 per 1 million, respectively, and in Cambodia, 40 and 270 respectively.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Poor and vulnerable people suffer more from extreme temperatures</h2>



<p>&#8220;Occupation, age, health status and disability, access to health care, socioeconomic status, even gender—all these factors make people more or less vulnerable,&#8221; says Chaya Bhadnaphuti, a geography lecturer at Chiang Mai University in Thailand and author of WWA.</p>



<p>Marginalized members of society, those without access to health care or access to cool air, and people who work outdoors in hot and humid weather, are most at risk.</p>



<p>According to a 2018 International Labor Organization (ILO) report, more than 60 percent of people in Southeast Asia work informally. This rate is 80 percent in Cambodia and Myanmar.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Advice to stay at home</h2>



<p>In late April, the Thai Health Department issued a wildfire warning. Mentioning the dangers of heat stroke, people in the capital Bangkok and other parts of the country are advised to stay at home during wildfires.</p>



<p>But for migrant workers like Supot Klongsap Nui, staying at home is not an option. He came to Bangkok from home to work as a construction worker. He said, this year is very hot, this year is different from other years.</p>



<p>Nooyi said construction workers including him usually live in houses with side walls and tin roofs. Such houses do not protect from heat. He cannot afford to live in an air-conditioned room.</p>



<p>A 2021 study found that in developing countries, those who work indoors have higher body temperatures than those who work outdoors. They are two or three times more prone to dehydration. There is a risk of damage to his kidneys and other related organs.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Livelihood threat</h2>



<p>Excessive smoking does not only harm a person&#8217;s health. Rather, it poses a threat to the environment and human livelihood. Harms air quality, destroys crops, increases wildfire risk and damages infrastructure. So it is very important to fix the action plan of any government during the crisis.</p>



<p>The livelihoods of people in the villages of Yotping and Phon in north-eastern Laos are deeply linked to the weather. The livelihood of the villagers revolves around the tea industry. Every day from 7 am to 11 pm they pick tea leaves. But due to excessive heat this year, they could not work in the morning. At this time they have to work in the afternoon. They are worried about the quantity of tea leaves. Because, the amount of their work has decreased. It also reduced income.</p>



<p>Lao Farmer Network&#8217;s managing officer Chintanaphon Keobichith said, this year is very hot. Farmers are now struggling with the heat.</p>



<p>Tea farmer Boa Seng said this year is much hotter than last year. The tea leaves are drying up.</p>



<p>Bing Samai Lobia Yao, manager of the 1,000-year-old tea processing factory, said that due to the heat this year, not enough tea leaves will be produced. This year the production will be 50 percent less than other years.</p>



<p>Global warming and pollution reduction is not possible without global concerted action. As the climate crisis escalates, the cost to individuals, society, the environment, health and the economy will be higher.</p>



<p>The month of June has started at the end of May. Many are still counting the days hoping for relief. Chintanaphon said, &#8216;May was the most terrible month. Rainy season usually starts in this month. But this year it hasn&#8217;t rained yet.&#8217;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/southeast-asia-has-not-seen-such-a-temperature-in-200-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jacinda Ardern got the title of &#8216;Dame&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/jacinda-ardern-got-the-title-of-dame/</link>
					<comments>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/jacinda-ardern-got-the-title-of-dame/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gambabu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 18:12:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Govt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/zolakaert/?p=38</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Zealand has awarded former Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern the title of &#8216;Dame&#8217;, one of the country&#8217;s highest honours. He was given the title on Monday for his role after the Christchurch mosque attack in 2019 and his leadership in the corona pandemic. The title Dame is primarily given to women. It is equivalent to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>New Zealand has awarded former Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern the title of &#8216;Dame&#8217;, one of the country&#8217;s highest honours. He was given the title on Monday for his role after the Christchurch mosque attack in 2019 and his leadership in the corona pandemic. The title Dame is primarily given to women. It is equivalent to the royal title of &#8216;knight&#8217;. &#8216;Knight&#8217; is one of the highest honors conferred by the King of the United Kingdom.</p>



<p>The 42-year-old Ardern announced her resignation from the post of Prime Minister of New Zealand and politics last January. Chris Hipkins became the Prime Minister of New Zealand as his successor. He said Ardern had been given the title of Dame, one of the country&#8217;s highest honours, at a ceremony marking the birthday and coronation of King Charles III.</p>



<p>Britain&#8217;s King Charles III was inaugurated on May 6. He is also the head of state of New Zealand.</p>



<p>Hipkins said Dame Jacinda Ardern served as Prime Minister of New Zealand from 2017 to 2013. He was recognized for the important role he played during the great challenges New Zealand has gone through in modern times.</p>



<p>On receiving the new title, Ardern said, &#8216;I was ambivalent about accepting this honour. Because most of these works are the product of the collective experience of New Zealanders.&#8217;</p>



<p>He was widely popular during the election of Prime Minister of New Zealand for a second term in 2020. But as the country&#8217;s inflation and cost of living rose, his popularity was waning. In this situation, he left the prime ministership and politics.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/jacinda-ardern-got-the-title-of-dame/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NPR’s Terence Samuel Is Named Top Editor of USA Today</title>
		<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/nprs-terence-samuel-is-named-top-editor-of-usa-today/</link>
					<comments>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/nprs-terence-samuel-is-named-top-editor-of-usa-today/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gambabu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 17:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Terence Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/myclimate/?p=27</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Terence Samuel, a top news executive at National Public Radio, will be the next editor in chief of USA Today. Gannett, the nation’s largest newspaper chain and the publisher of USA Today, made the announcement on Friday. Mr. Samuel, who will start on July 10, fills a position vacated in May by Nicole Carroll, who had [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Terence Samuel, a top news executive at National Public Radio, will be the next editor in chief of USA Today.</p>



<p>Gannett, the nation’s largest newspaper chain and the publisher of USA Today, made the announcement on Friday. Mr. Samuel, who will start on July 10, fills a position vacated in May by Nicole Carroll, who had led USA Today for five years.</p>



<p>Mr. Samuel, 61, is a vice president and executive editor at NPR, where he oversees all news gathering at the network. Before joining NPR in 2017, he was a deputy national political editor at The Washington Post, and he has also worked at The Root, The Philadelphia Inquirer and U.S. News &amp; World Report.</p>



<p>Mr. Samuel said in a statement that he was honored to help lead USA Today, which made its debut in 1982, “into a digital future.”</p>



<p>“USA Today has a distinctive and groundbreaking history in American journalism and is uniquely positioned to inform the conversations and tell the stories that impact American life,” he said.</p>



<p>Kristin Roberts, Gannett’s chief content officer, said Mr. Samuel would “accelerate our transformation of USA Today, embracing our role and our roots as America’s newspaper with the core mission of being nothing less than essential to the readers, viewers and listeners we serve nationwide.”</p>



<p>In an email to NPR staff on Friday, Edith Chapin, the interim senior vice president for news, said the network would conduct a national search to find his replacement.</p>



<p>Mr. Samuel joins Gannett at a perilous time. The company, struggling under a debt burden from its 2019 merger with GateHouse Media, has had multiple rounds of layoffs in recent years. Its stock price has plummeted nearly 70 percent since the merger.</p>



<p>Hundreds of journalists from about two dozen Gannett newsrooms plan to walk off the job on Monday during the company’s annual shareholder meeting in protest over its executive leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/nprs-terence-samuel-is-named-top-editor-of-usa-today/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Debt ceiling deal reveals the impotence of Donald Trump&#8217;s MAGA movement</title>
		<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/debt-ceiling-deal-reveals-the-impotence-of-donald-trumps-maga-movement/</link>
					<comments>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/debt-ceiling-deal-reveals-the-impotence-of-donald-trumps-maga-movement/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gambabu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 17:39:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MAGA movement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[McCarthy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/myclimate/?p=24</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have bad news for folks who invested in bright red “Make America Great Again” hats and devoted years of their lives to what former President Donald Trump routinely calls “the greatest political movement in the history of our country.” The MAGA movement, with each passing day, appears smaller and more impotent. It’s loud but ineffective, capable [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I have bad news for folks who invested in bright red “Make America Great Again” hats and devoted years of their lives to what former President Donald Trump routinely calls “the greatest political movement in the history of our country.”</p>



<p>The MAGA movement, with each passing day, appears smaller and more impotent. It’s loud but ineffective, capable of creating chaos but incapable of success.</p>



<p>The recent debt ceiling deal reached between President Joe Biden and Republican House Speaker Kevin McCarthy perfectly illustrates MAGA’s all-holler/no-action status.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">MAGA&#8217;s debt ceiling red line was easily crossed by Kevin McCarthy</h2>



<p>This was the none-shall-pass moment for far-right Republicans in Congress, a chance to use the threat of economic disaster that would accompany a default to undo all the things Big Bad Biden has accomplished as president, to slash spending to the bone and poke holes in the safety net.</p>



<p>“I say to the Republicans out there – congressmen, senators – if they don’t give you massive cuts, you’re going to have to do a default,&#8221; Trump said during a CNN town hall.</p>



<p>Republican Rep. Kevin Hern of Oklahoma, chair of the Republican Study Committee told Axios that he agreed with Trump. And Rep. Ralph Norman of South Carolina said: “Either they agree to cuts, which are modest, or they take responsibility for whatever happens.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Republican Party&#8217;s debt ceiling threats met up with reality</h2>



<p>McCarthy caved to MAGA demands and initially produced a debt ceiling bill that would have gutted much of what Biden accomplished in his first two years. It was a wholly unreasonable proposal, aimed at appeasing the extremes of McCarthy&#8217;s own party.</p>



<p>But the final deal the speaker hammered out with Biden was nothing close to what MAGA lawmakers wanted.</p>



<p><strong>Trump unleashes DeSantis deepfake:</strong>GOP should support a grownup for president.</p>



<p><strong>Game on.</strong>With DeSantis making it official on Twitter, the fight against Trump can begin.</p>



<p>The original bill sought a 10-year cap on spending, with draconian cuts to non-Defense spending. The final deal puts minor spending restraints in place for the next two years. They wanted strict (and unnecessary) work requirements on food stamps recipients and people on Medicaid. Medicaid went untouched, and the dynamics of the change in work requirements for Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program recipients, according to the nonpartisan Congressional Budget Office, will actually increase government spending on food stamps.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/debt-ceiling-deal-reveals-the-impotence-of-donald-trumps-maga-movement/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saudi Arabia is reducing oil production, there is a fear of price increase</title>
		<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/saudi-arabia-is-reducing-oil-production-there-is-a-fear-of-price-increase/</link>
					<comments>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/saudi-arabia-is-reducing-oil-production-there-is-a-fear-of-price-increase/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gambabu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 16:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the oil]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/ntt-com/?p=17</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia has announced to reduce oil production by another 1 million barrels per day. It is believed that such a decision has been taken to increase the price of oil in the world market by reducing the supply. The announcement was made after a meeting between the 13-nation Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Saudi Arabia has announced to reduce oil production by another 1 million barrels per day. It is believed that such a decision has been taken to increase the price of oil in the world market by reducing the supply.</p>



<p>The announcement was made after a meeting between the 13-nation Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) and its 10 allies led by Saudi Arabia. Russia led the Allies. OPEC and 10 allied countries are called OPEC Plus.</p>



<p>Saudi Arabia&#8217;s Energy Minister Prince Abdulaziz bin Salman told reporters that the decision to cut production was made for the month of July. Its duration may be extended.</p>



<p>The decision to cut &#8216;voluntary&#8217; production was announced after representatives of OPEC plus countries took part in several hours of talks in the Austrian capital Vienna.</p>



<p>A source involved in this discussion says that there has been a discussion about reducing production by 1 million barrels per day.</p>



<p>About 60 percent of the world&#8217;s total oil is produced in OPEC plus countries. Oil-producing nations have struggled to cope with falling oil prices and volatile markets since Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine began in February 2022.</p>



<p>Last April, several OPEC Plus members agreed to voluntarily cut production by more than 1 million barrels a day. Although this sudden action reduced the price of oil, it was not sustainable for long.<br>Oil prices fell nearly 10 percent after announcing production cuts in April. Brent crude oil prices fell to $70 per barrel. This is the first time since December 2021 that the price of Brent crude has fallen so much.</p>



<p>Russian Deputy Prime Minister Alexander Novak said that the current decision to cut production may be extended until the end of 2024 after testing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/saudi-arabia-is-reducing-oil-production-there-is-a-fear-of-price-increase/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Record of foreigners taking citizenship in Germany</title>
		<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/record-of-foreigners-taking-citizenship-in-germany/</link>
					<comments>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/record-of-foreigners-taking-citizenship-in-germany/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gambabu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 16:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/ntt-com/?p=14</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A record number of foreigners took up citizenship in Germany last year. This number is the highest in the last 20 years. According to the government&#8217;s calculations, in 2022, 168,545 people from 171 countries of the world took German citizenship. This number is 28 percent more than the previous year, i.e. 2021. Syrians top the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A record number of foreigners took up citizenship in Germany last year. This number is the highest in the last 20 years.</p>



<p>According to the government&#8217;s calculations, in 2022, 168,545 people from 171 countries of the world took German citizenship. This number is 28 percent more than the previous year, i.e. 2021.</p>



<p>Syrians top the list of foreigners granted citizenship. The average age of people who have taken German citizenship from the war-torn Middle Eastern country is 25 years (24.8). Two-thirds of them are men. They stayed in the country for an average of six and a half years (6.4) before getting citizenship.</p>



<p>Ukrainians are second in the list of German citizens. Thousands of Ukrainians fled the country after the Russian offensive began. A part of them took refuge in Germany.</p>



<p>In 2022, immigrants from Iraq, another war-torn country in the Middle East, ranked third among immigrants who received German citizenship. And the Turks are in the fourth position.</p>



<p>Ian Schneider, an expert at the Department of Integration and Migration, said that half of the Syrians who got citizenship got German citizenship within six years. The reason for this is that they have been able to show evidence of integration into German society.</p>



<p>According to Schleider, the German citizenship of Syrians will increase this year. Because, the current coalition government in power is working to simplify the citizenship law.</p>



<p>Currently, in order to obtain German citizenship, a candidate must demonstrate eight years of residence in Germany and proof of German language proficiency (B1 level). Along with passing a special written test for citizenship. Apart from this, there is a requirement to have the financial ability to operate without state aid and to have no criminal record.</p>



<p>However, due to the shortage of skilled workers in the country, the ruling coalition government led by Olaf Schultz is trying to amend the citizenship law. The government believes that easing citizenship laws will encourage skilled foreign workers to immigrate to the country.</p>



<p>Interior Minister Nancy Fesser&#8217;s proposed new citizenship law calls for three major changes.</p>



<p>Under the proposed new law, citizenship can be applied for after five years of legal residence in Germany instead of eight. Apart from this, there is an opportunity to apply after three years of residence if you can show proof of integration in the society.</p>



<p>If one of the parents of a child born in Germany has lived legally in the country for five years, the child is eligible for German citizenship.</p>



<p>Apart from this, it is said that the facility of holding dual citizenship is also being kept in the new law.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/record-of-foreigners-taking-citizenship-in-germany/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Austin-Rajnath discussed military alliance</title>
		<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/austin-rajnath-discussed-military-alliance/</link>
					<comments>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/austin-rajnath-discussed-military-alliance/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gambabu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 15:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[defense]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/ntt-com/?p=10</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[India and the US have jointly decided on a direction to move forward in expanding areas of cooperation in defense manufacturing and technology transfer. US Defense Minister Austin Lloyd&#8217;s two-day visit to India held a detailed discussion on this issue on Monday. After talks with India&#8217;s Defense Minister Rajnath Singh, US Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>India and the US have jointly decided on a direction to move forward in expanding areas of cooperation in defense manufacturing and technology transfer. US Defense Minister Austin Lloyd&#8217;s two-day visit to India held a detailed discussion on this issue on Monday.</p>



<p>After talks with India&#8217;s Defense Minister Rajnath Singh, US Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin told media representatives, &#8216;The relationship between the two countries is improving rapidly. We are now looking at expanding the scope of defense industry cooperation.&#8217;</p>



<p>The main objective of this cooperation in defense manufacturing is to make India &#8216;self-reliant&#8217; and implement the &#8216;Make in India&#8217; slogan. After the &#8216;warm and sincere&#8217; meeting of the two defense ministers, the statement of the Ministry of Defense of India said that policy guidelines have been prepared for how the two countries will expand the area of ​​mutual cooperation in the next few years. Accordingly, the two countries will identify new technology-based defense production areas. Emphasis will also be placed on technology transfer to scale up production.</p>



<p>The two leaders also discussed enhancing defense ties. After the meeting, Indian Defense Minister Rajnath Singh said that it is important to keep India and the Pacific region under free, unfettered and legal governance and deepen the relationship between the two countries to ensure that. For that, India is ready to work more closely with the US to build strategic ties and enhance defense capabilities.</p>



<p>Before the visit, it was reported by informed sources that General Electric of the United States is interested in transferring the technology of manufacturing fighter aircraft engines to India. Apart from this, India has also shown interest in buying 30 &#8216;MQ-9B&#8217; armed drones from the US for $3 billion. These issues will be considered during the visit to Austin. However, after the meeting of the two ministers, nothing specific was said about it. However, it is believed that the US Defense Secretary&#8217;s visit is very indicative ahead of Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi&#8217;s upcoming US visit.<br>Russia supplies the bulk of India&#8217;s defense equipment and armaments. Despite that long-standing relationship, India has also started buying military weapons from the US, France and Israel over the years.</p>



<p>Before coming to India, Austin attended the &#8216;Sangri La Dialogue&#8217;, a security summit in Singapore. China&#8217;s Defense Minister Li Shangfu warned that the formation of a military alliance like &#8220;NATO&#8221; in the Asia-Pacific region will plunge the entire region into a whirlwind of conflict. The United States has taken steps to create a NATO-like military alliance in the region to counter China&#8217;s speculation. They are keen to include India in that alliance.</p>



<p>While Rajnath Singh&#8217;s meeting with Austin discussed keeping the Indo-Pacific region &#8216;fear-free and free&#8217;, there was no word from any quarter on whether the proposal to form a military alliance like NATO was discussed or not. Lloyd Austin also held a meeting with India&#8217;s National Security Advisor Ajit Doval today.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/austin-rajnath-discussed-military-alliance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The president of Barca took away the journalist&#8217;s phone for questioning Messi&#8217;s return</title>
		<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/the-president-of-barca-took-away-the-journalists-phone-for-questioning-messis-return/</link>
					<comments>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/the-president-of-barca-took-away-the-journalists-phone-for-questioning-messis-return/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gambabu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 15:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barcelona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[messi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PSG]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/ntt-com/?p=7</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One question the football world has already answered is whether Lionel Messi&#8217;s two-year relationship with PSG has ended. There is also a question about Messi, which is now a question of billions of dollars in the football world &#8211; where will Messi go? Al Hilal officials are currently in Paris, according to news agency AFP. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>One question the football world has already answered is whether Lionel Messi&#8217;s two-year relationship with PSG has ended. There is also a question about Messi, which is now a question of billions of dollars in the football world &#8211; where will Messi go?</p>



<p>Al Hilal officials are currently in Paris, according to news agency AFP. They went there to talk to Messi&#8217;s father and agent Jorge Messi to finalize the deal. AFP wrote in their news that the official announcement of the finalization of the contract will be made by the Saudi Arabian club before the beginning of the week.</p>



<p>Even with such news, there is no shortage of expectations about Messi&#8217;s return to Barcelona. The club&#8217;s supporters at Camp Nou are still hoping that Messi will return. Messi signed from Barcelona to PSG in 2021. While AFP is reporting on the final stage of the contract with Al Hilal on the Argentine World Cup-winning star, journalists close to Barcelona are asking the president of the club, Juan Laporta, what is the probability of Messi&#8217;s return?</p>



<p>Laporta was asked this question yesterday by a journalist who turned on his cell phone recorder to record what Laporta said. Then Laporta showed a strange reaction.</p>



<p>According to Argentinian media TYC, Laporta grabbed the journalist&#8217;s phone and put it in his pocket. Then he said, &#8216;You will see if it is difficult to return Messi.&#8217; After a while, however, Laporta returned the journalist&#8217;s mobile phone.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/the-president-of-barca-took-away-the-journalists-phone-for-questioning-messis-return/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
