<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Asia &#8211; WW Cam Britannica</title>
	<atom:link href="https://ww.cam.britannica.com/tag/asia/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 05:31:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/wwcam.png</url>
	<title>Asia &#8211; WW Cam Britannica</title>
	<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Southeast Asia has not seen such a temperature in 200 years</title>
		<link>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/southeast-asia-has-not-seen-such-a-temperature-in-200-years/</link>
					<comments>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/southeast-asia-has-not-seen-such-a-temperature-in-200-years/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gambabu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 05:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temperature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Translation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/top85/?p=50</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fires were intense in South and Southeast Asia in April and May. That blaze is still going on. Due to heat and humidity, the people of this region are at high risk of heat stroke, heart disease, kidney problems and even death due to dehydration. CNN&#8217;s Sarlotta Doto , Christina Schweda and Lou Robinson detail the story . Every day countless mopeds (motorcycles [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Fires were intense in South and Southeast Asia in April and May. That blaze is still going on. Due to heat and humidity, the people of this region are at high risk of heat stroke, heart disease, kidney problems and even death due to dehydration. <strong>CNN&#8217;s Sarlotta Doto</strong> , <strong>Christina Schweda</strong> and <strong>Lou Robinson</strong> detail the story .</p>



<p>Every day countless mopeds (motorcycles with pedals) and motorbikes ply the busy streets of Hanoi, Vietnam. Some are going to work, some are transporting passengers. Others are delivering parcels or food to consumers.</p>



<p>One such person is Fong (42). At five in the morning he started working with the moped. He left for work early in the morning to escape the unbearable heat. Worked for 12 hours straight.</p>



<p>But in the last two months, terrible fires have engulfed the entire country. Temperatures hover around 40 degrees Celsius (104 degrees Fahrenheit) every day. This unbearable situation made Fong&#8217;s job very difficult. Wear a hat while going out to work to protect yourself from the extreme heat. Keep wet towels and a few bottles of water with you.</p>



<p>Temperatures in Hanoi averaged over 32 degrees Celsius throughout the month of May.</p>



<p>Fong was saying, &#8216;I have to stop working if I get heat stroke. My family won&#8217;t survive in this.&#8217;</p>



<p>Fong uses a small umbrella to protect the mobile phone, the most important part of his job, from the heat. He uses ride sharing app &#8216;Grub&#8217; platform for work. If the phone breaks for some reason or the battery gets damaged due to heat, his income<br>will be cut off.</p>



<p>Din Van Hung (53) was working as a cleaner in Dong Da area of ​​Hanoi. He cleaned the garbage on the busy road throughout the day. Din Bhan said, &#8216;Dry heat cannot be avoided in the afternoon and early afternoon. Excessive temperature emits an unbearable odor from garbage. My job has become more difficult now. The heat is having an adverse effect on the health of me and other workers.&#8217;</p>



<p>Din Bhan added, &#8216;I try to start work early in the morning and in the afternoon or evening. In the afternoon when the temperature is at extremes, I take shade on the sidewalk. Then in the afternoon I started working again.&#8217;</p>



<p>In Southeast Asia, including Vietnam, Phong and Din Bhan are the image of millions of people working in the open air, including drivers, hawkers, cleaners, construction workers, farmers. They have to work under record pressure.</p>



<p>These workers suffer disproportionately in such adverse weather conditions. The extreme heat is affecting their health and has already made their occupation dangerous.</p>



<p>Generally, April and May are the hottest months in Southeast Asian countries. The temperature rises considerably in this region before the onset of monsoon rains. But this time the temperature has reached a level that has never been seen before. The tourism industry of Thailand and Vietnam is also affected.</p>



<p>Maximiliano Herrera, who works on climate, analyzed the weather data and said that on April 15, Thailand had the highest temperature in the country&#8217;s history at 45.4 degrees Celsius (114 degrees Fahrenheit). Similarly, neighboring Laos recorded two consecutive days of 43.5 degrees Celsius (110 degrees Fahrenheit) in May. And at the beginning of May, Vietnam had the highest temperature in the history of that country, which was 44.2 degrees Celsius.</p>



<p>Herrera described the situation as an &#8216;unending barrage of brutality&#8217;. According to him, this fire will continue throughout the month of June. Vietnam broke the record for the hottest June in their history (43.8 degrees Celsius) on June 1. Time will tell what will happen in the remaining 29 days.</p>



<p>According to a report by World Weather Attribution (WWA), an international alliance of scientists, the kind of fire that is going on in Southeast Asia is seen once in 200 years. But such a scenario is &#8216;virtually impossible&#8217; without man-made climate change.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Damage is more in humidity</h2>



<p>The scorching heat can become even more unbearable in Southeast Asia due to high humidity. Because, humidity with high temperature increases the heat in the human body and the body does not cool down easily.</p>



<p>Heat related illnesses such as heat stroke, fatigue are not good signs. It can be life threatening. Pregnant women, heart patients, kidney patients and people with diabetes are especially at risk.</p>



<p>Mariam Zakaria, research associate at Imperial College London, said, &#8220;When the humidity is too high, the body sweats to cool itself down.&#8221; But due to non-evaporation of sweat, severe dehydration occurs in the body. If it becomes severe it can lead to heat stroke and even death. This is why humid heat is more dangerous than dry heat.</p>



<p>To understand the human health risks of humid heat, scientists usually calculate the &#8216;feels-like&#8217; temperature. They factor in both temperature and humidity to calculate how it feels. Wind speed is also often taken into account.</p>



<p>The perceived temperature is often much higher than the normal temperature. Much more accurate information is available from the perceived temperature of how much it affects the human body.</p>



<p>Six Southeast Asian countries (Thailand, Vietnam, Cambodia, Laos, Malaysia and Myanmar) experienced daily temperatures of 40 degrees Celsius or more between early April and late May, according to an analysis of data from the Copernicus Climate Change Service. This level is considered above the risk limit. People with health problems and not used to such heat are particularly at risk.</p>



<p>Thailand experienced 20 days in April and 10 days in May with temperatures above 46 degrees Celsius. Temperatures at this stage are quite &#8216;extreme&#8217; and are considered life-threatening. If there is moisture with it, there is no question.</p>



<p>Vietnam, Cambodia, Laos and Malaysia experienced extreme temperatures during April–May. Before the cyclone cleared, there was a near-fire in Myanmar for 12 days.</p>



<p>According to World Weather Attribution, wildfires in Southeast Asia in April–May caused illness, road damage<br>, fires, and school closures. However, not much is known about the actual death toll.</p>



<p>According to the agency&#8217;s report, the perceived temperature is 2 degrees above normal due to climate change.</p>



<p>Mariam Zakaria, one of the authors of World Weather Attribution, said that as the atmosphere warms, its capacity to hold moisture increases. It also increases the risk of humid heat waves.</p>



<p>According to the report, if global warming continues to increase by 2 degrees Celsius, humid temperatures could increase 10 times.</p>



<p>Projections from the United Nations&#8217; Human Climate Horizons show that if temperatures rise at the same rate, fires in Thailand will kill 30 people per million in two decades and more than 130 people by the end of this century. In the case of Myanmar, these numbers will be 30 and 520 per 1 million, respectively, and in Cambodia, 40 and 270 respectively.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Poor and vulnerable people suffer more from extreme temperatures</h2>



<p>&#8220;Occupation, age, health status and disability, access to health care, socioeconomic status, even gender—all these factors make people more or less vulnerable,&#8221; says Chaya Bhadnaphuti, a geography lecturer at Chiang Mai University in Thailand and author of WWA.</p>



<p>Marginalized members of society, those without access to health care or access to cool air, and people who work outdoors in hot and humid weather, are most at risk.</p>



<p>According to a 2018 International Labor Organization (ILO) report, more than 60 percent of people in Southeast Asia work informally. This rate is 80 percent in Cambodia and Myanmar.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Advice to stay at home</h2>



<p>In late April, the Thai Health Department issued a wildfire warning. Mentioning the dangers of heat stroke, people in the capital Bangkok and other parts of the country are advised to stay at home during wildfires.</p>



<p>But for migrant workers like Supot Klongsap Nui, staying at home is not an option. He came to Bangkok from home to work as a construction worker. He said, this year is very hot, this year is different from other years.</p>



<p>Nooyi said construction workers including him usually live in houses with side walls and tin roofs. Such houses do not protect from heat. He cannot afford to live in an air-conditioned room.</p>



<p>A 2021 study found that in developing countries, those who work indoors have higher body temperatures than those who work outdoors. They are two or three times more prone to dehydration. There is a risk of damage to his kidneys and other related organs.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Livelihood threat</h2>



<p>Excessive smoking does not only harm a person&#8217;s health. Rather, it poses a threat to the environment and human livelihood. Harms air quality, destroys crops, increases wildfire risk and damages infrastructure. So it is very important to fix the action plan of any government during the crisis.</p>



<p>The livelihoods of people in the villages of Yotping and Phon in north-eastern Laos are deeply linked to the weather. The livelihood of the villagers revolves around the tea industry. Every day from 7 am to 11 pm they pick tea leaves. But due to excessive heat this year, they could not work in the morning. At this time they have to work in the afternoon. They are worried about the quantity of tea leaves. Because, the amount of their work has decreased. It also reduced income.</p>



<p>Lao Farmer Network&#8217;s managing officer Chintanaphon Keobichith said, this year is very hot. Farmers are now struggling with the heat.</p>



<p>Tea farmer Boa Seng said this year is much hotter than last year. The tea leaves are drying up.</p>



<p>Bing Samai Lobia Yao, manager of the 1,000-year-old tea processing factory, said that due to the heat this year, not enough tea leaves will be produced. This year the production will be 50 percent less than other years.</p>



<p>Global warming and pollution reduction is not possible without global concerted action. As the climate crisis escalates, the cost to individuals, society, the environment, health and the economy will be higher.</p>



<p>The month of June has started at the end of May. Many are still counting the days hoping for relief. Chintanaphon said, &#8216;May was the most terrible month. Rainy season usually starts in this month. But this year it hasn&#8217;t rained yet.&#8217;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://ww.cam.britannica.com/southeast-asia-has-not-seen-such-a-temperature-in-200-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
